

# **GOWTHAM RAJAN N**

# **Structural Engineer**

"Curious, motivated and determined"

+91 9751458643 gowthama.ga75@gmail.com

gowtham-rajan-n-699678192

# **OBJECTIVE**

Dedicative learner with a high track record and outstanding performance in academics. I intend to be part of an organization where I can constantly develop my technical and management skills to make the best use of it for the growth of the society.

#### INTEREST

Aviation, Design. Innovation, Project Management

## **ROLE & EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Responsible for the static analysis, Fatigue life, Crack propagation estimation and reserve factor determination in various components of fuselage, wings, pylon, and other parts of commercial aircrafts.

- Experience in Metallic and composite Static strength calculation.
- Experience in DFEM load Extractions and obtained FDT equivalent stresses using Spectrum.
- Experience in Build stress extraction, Fatigue life calculation and Stress Corrosion Cracking.
- Experience in ACD sheet preparation using ACD tool.

#### **SKILLS**

•	Auto-CAD	<ul> <li>MS Office, Excel VBA</li> </ul>	

**Tamil** 

Solidworks, CATIA

Python, C, Power apps

**English** 

ANSYS, MATLAB

Airbus ISAMI, ACD Tool

French

MSc Patran, Nastran

German Hyperworks

# WORK EXPERIENCE

Mar. 2022 – Present Engineer – (Aerospace Structural)

Sep. 2021 – Mar. 2022 Graduate Trainee Engineer – (Aerospace Structural)

# **EDUCATION**

Aug. 2017 - May. 2021 Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical) – 9.02 CGPA

Coimbatore, India Hindusthan College of Engineering and Technology, Anna University

HSC - 86% & SSLC - 98% Jun. 2014 – May 2017

Perambalur, India Sri Ramakrishna Matric Higher Secondary School

# HONOURS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- ✓ Secured all India 2nd position in Saur Urja Vehicle Challenge organized by RSTE Engineers.
- ✓ Secured all India 1st position in Rally Car Design Challenge conducted in Bikaner (Desert), Rajasthan.

# **PROJECTS**

Oct. 2021 – Dec. 2021	Static Strength Calculation in Nose Landing Gear Bay upper panel (A319/A320/A321)
Dec. 2021 – Feb. 2022	DFEM Extractions; FDT equivalent stress calculation using Spectrum (A350 Serial 1000- STEP6 and STEP7)
Mar. 2022 – May. 2022	Build Stress Extraction, Fatigue life Calculation and SCC (A319/A320/A321XLR/NEO)

### TRAINING EXPERIENCE

Apr. 2021 – Aug. 2021	<b>Undergraduate Research Assistant</b>

Coimbatore, India Hindusthan College of Engineering and Technology.

Feb. 2021 – Mar. 2021 **Internee** 

Coimbatore, India Schneider Electric India Pvt LTD (A Unit of L&T Electrical and Automation).

**Nov** 2019 – **Dec** 2019 **Internee** 

Coimbatore, India Messer Cutting Systems India Pvt Limited.

Nov. 2018 – Dec. 2018 In-plant Trainee

Coimbatore, India ROOTS Industries India Pvt Limited.

# **COURSE COMPLETIONS**

Completed an online course in Coursera and NPTEL about Self Driving Cars, Engineering Mechanics, Wind Energy, Engineering Project Management, Mechanics of Materials, Product Design & Development, Generative Design, Digitalization in Aerospace Industry, Model Based System Engineering. Supply Chain Management, Excel Skills for Business: Essentials, Excel/VBA for Creative Problem Solving, Data Processing using Python.

# **CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS AND PRESENTATIONS**

- ✓ Presented a research paper in the International Web Conference on Smart Engineering Technologies about Solar Powered Electric Vehicle.
- ✓ Presented a research paper in "International Virtual Conference of Recent Innovations in Science, Engineering and Technology" about Design and Development of All-Terrain Electric Vehicles.
- ✓ Presented a research paper in "AICTE Sponsored E-Conference on Systems Modelling and System Dynamics" Design and Development of All-Terrain Electric Vehicles.

#### **EXTRA-CURRICULAR**

- ✓ Participated in SUPRA, E-BAJA, BAJA, Formula-1 Vehicle Competition, organized by SAE India in JUN 2019.
- ✓ Volunteer in the National Service Scheme funded by the Government of India.